Vineeth Foregard



•

Summary

Cleared Full-stack developer with 4 years of experience in designing, implementing, maintaining, and testing object-oriented applications for production-ready web projects in both DoD and industry environments. Passionate about clean, efficient code and attentive to detail, consistently delivering well-structured and maintainable solutions.

Experience

Naval Information Warfare Center Pacific

Software Engineer (Full Time) - Philadelphia, PA

01/2023 - Present

- Led the development of a TRL 9-certified application that improved user efficiency by 500%, saving customer over 150 hours weekly and driving significant operational cost savings.
- Addressed a critical issue by implementing Amazon S3 buckets for image retrieval and upload, resolving production crashes and reducing API retrieval time from ~7 seconds to ~300ms, significantly improving stability.
- Implemented complex data structures to streamline multiple API calls into a single call, enhancing system efficiency and performance.
- Developed and implemented CI/CD pipelines leveraging AWS ECS, ECR, and SDK, automating containerized application deployments and configuration to streamline release cycles and ensure rapid, consistent updates in cloud environments.
- Authored a comprehensive test suite with over 90% test coverage to validate functionality using JUnit, Jest, React Testing Library, and Cypress, improving code quality, and enhancing overall software reliability.
- Implemented 180+ secure development practices adhering to NIST and OWASP guidelines, utilizing various SCA tools, including Fortify, SonarQube, and TruffleHog.
- Member of various division councils and working groups, contributing to workforce development.
- Chaired the software development council, fostering a collaborative community of 10+ engineers focused on emerging technologies, software landscape assessment, and facilitating presentations on ongoing projects.

Data Intelligence LLC

Full-Stack Developer (Full Time) - Marlton, NJ

07/2020 - 01/2023

- Designed and developed multiple scalable feature products on KesselRun's Targeting and Geointelligence portfolio through full stack with Pair Programming techniques.
- Harnessed React Context API, React Hooks and Redux to inject state into deeply nested components to minimize
 prop drilling, handle asynchronous behavior and maintain state throughout the application while reducing
 extraneous code.
- Employed Test Driven Development (TDD) methodology using Jasmine, React testing library and Cypress to create unit and integration tests in order to expedite code review and allow for code refactoring and new features development while ensuring ready-to-deploy-code without any undirected side-effects.
- Used Concourse and Gitlab for CI/CD, employing automated builds into pipelines to improve test-coverage and time-to-production with instantaneous feedback.

CAT Technology

Java Developer (Internship - Full Time) - Hackensack, NJ

12/2019 - 06/2020

- Analysis, Design, Development, System Testing and User Acceptance testing following agile methodology in the Scrum Cycle model.
- Designed and developed API's using REST framework and Spring Boot.
- Used Spring framework including Spring core, Spring Web, Spring Security for authentication, authorization, and access-control features.
- · Used Microservices to communicate using synchronous protocols HTTP and REST for implementing SOA.

U / 1 U

Skills

React, Typescript, Java, Springboot, Python, JDBC, React Testing Library, Jest, Junit, Cypress, Kubernetes, ApachePOI, Gradle/Maven, UI/UX Design, Scrum, Axios, CI/CD, Gitlab Pipelines, NPM, OAuth, Rest API's, Docker, AWS, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Yarn, Redis

Education

Computer Science

City University of New York, Brooklyn College Brooklyn

12/2020

Information Technology

Kingsborough Community College Brooklyn

Certificates

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner – Foundational, Comptia Security+ - August 2022

Projects

Perceptron (Dec 2019)

- Built a Multi Layer Perceptron model that predicts exchange rate between USD and Euro.
- Prediction of Public Transportation Reliability based on Weather Jan 2020
- Used the MBTA reliability metrics and NOAA Climate data to train a regression model and Decision Tree Classifier.
- Utilized D3.js to allow users to dynamically visualize the reliability of a particular mode of transport on a given data.
- Used pandas and numpy to extract useful information from raw data.